<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 1/16/2014 11:54:41 PM -->
<GameData>
  <Language_en_US>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Nazi Germany
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_NAZI_GERMANY_DESC">
			<Text>The Third Reich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_NAZI_GERMANY_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Nazi Germany</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_NAZI_GERMANY_ADJ">
			<Text>Nazi German</Text>
		</Row>
		 <!-- Spy Names -->
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_9">
			<Text>Dasch</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_8">
			<Text>Lilly</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_7">
			<Text>Grimpel</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_6">
			<Text>Colepaugh</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_5">
			<Text>Othmer</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_4">
			<Text>Guenther</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_3">
			<Text>Dr. Griebl</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_2">
			<Text>Hermann</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_1">
			<Text>Guellich</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_0">
			<Text>Josef</Text>
		 </Row>
		 <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_NAZI_10">
			<Text>Duquesne</Text>
		 </Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Hitler
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER">
			<Text>Hitler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_HITLER_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_HITLER_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Adolf Hitler was an Austrian-born German politician and the leader of the Nazi Party (National Socialist German Workers Party). He was chancellor of Germany from 1933 to 1945 and dictator of Nazi Germany (as Führer und Reichskanzler) from 1934 to 1945. Hitler was at the centre of Nazi Germany, World War II in Europe, and the Holocaust.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hitler was a decorated veteran of World War I. He joined the German Workers' Party (precursor of the NSDAP) in 1919, and became leader of the NSDAP in 1921. In 1923, he attempted a coup d'état in Munich, known as the Beer Hall Putsch. The failed coup resulted in Hitler's imprisonment, during which time he wrote his memoir, Mein Kampf (My Struggle). After his release in 1924, Hitler gained popular support by attacking the Treaty of Versailles and promoting Pan-Germanism, antisemitism, and anti-communism with charismatic oratory and Nazi propaganda. After his appointment as chancellor in 1933, he transformed the Weimar Republic into the Third Reich, a single-party dictatorship based on the totalitarian and autocratic ideology of Nazism.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hitler's aim was to establish a New Order of absolute Nazi German hegemony in continental Europe. To this end, his foreign and domestic policies had the aim of seizing Lebensraum ("living space") for the Germanic people. He directed the rearmament of Germany and the invasion of Poland by the Wehrmacht in September 1939, resulting in the outbreak of World War II in Europe. Under Hitler's rule, in 1941 German forces and their European allies occupied most of Europe and North Africa. In June 1941, Hitler ordered an invasion of the Soviet Union. Although initially successful, the Russian campaign turned disastrous. By 1943, Germany was forced onto the defensive and suffered a series of escalating defeats. In the final days of the war, during the Battle of Berlin in 1945, Hitler married his long-time partner, Eva Braun. On 30 April 1945, less than two days later, the two committed suicide to avoid capture by the Red Army, and their corpses were burned.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hitler's aggressive foreign policy is considered to be the primary cause of the outbreak of World War II in Europe. Under Hitler's leadership and racially motivated ideology, the regime was responsible for the genocide of at least 5.5 million Jews, and millions of other people whom he and his followers deemed racially inferior.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_HITLER_LIVED">
			<Text>1889 - 1945 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_HITLER_NAME">
			<Text>Adolf Hitler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_HITLER_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Germany</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Führer of Germany, Reichsstatthalter of Prussia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_JFD_HITLER_TEXT">
			<Text>Adolf Hitler, grave salutations be upon you. The story of the German people is one of the battered and the bruised; one of countless great empires suffocated by the would-be powers that command Europe. Your people are a great culture, and you have pledged yourself to their burden. Noble Germany yearns for one with such passion as yours; to be the voice of her plight, and to re-awaken her dormant power and to carve her name into the backs of those who have spoken it in mockery. At your command, a new, glorious age for the German people has dawned.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mighty leader, your people demand that their noble claim to this earth be delivered unto them. Can you rise above the shadows of Germany's foes? Can you march her armies across this earth until it kneels to her command? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Diplomacy
		--------------------------------------------------------------- --->
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Adolf Hitler, Chancellor of Germany and leader of the German people. So let's talk about the land which you mistakenly believe to be yours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>What? Who is this? You cannot just waltz into Germany like this without an appointment. Do you know who I am? I am Adolf Hitler.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>There will be consequences to this defeat! I assure you!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>You're getting on my nerves. Go bother somebody else.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_REPEAT_TRADE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>I already told you to only bother offering a deal that is better for me than it is for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Ugh, what is it?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Yes?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I see that consequences have met you. Hehee. I hope you lose your war badly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>What do you want? Come to beg for my aide to intervene in your pathetic war?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>You will withdraw your military action near to my empire, or there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>The land that you are mindlessly purchasing forms a part of the ancestry of the German people. Continue, and there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>The land that you are mindlessly purchasing forms a part of the ancestry of the German people. Continue, and there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>The spread of your cities and people is like a plague infecting the land. I look forward to the day I don't have to see it any more.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>Your imperialism is getting on my nerves. Stop it at once or there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>I have been told you have a powerful military. Looking at you, I doubt it to be true.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>Yes, you may have a strong economy now, but will it be enough to face the coming storm?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES_1">
			<Text>You're the captain of San Marino, yes? You have so few cities, you cannot expect me to think you rule a real nation, can you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY_1">
			<Text>Your military is pathetic; your soldiers shudder at the blast of cannon-fire and their uniforms are soaked in urine. Why don't you pack it in and surrender while your own pants are still dry?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>You nasty warmonger. You've been very nasty. Hehee.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_1">
			<Text>I will declare no such thing with the likes of you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You're worse than... well, you're worse than me![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DENOUNCE_2">
			<Text>You should have subjected yourself to my supremacy while you had the chance. Now your wretchedness will be exposed to the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>So you have chosen the way of the fool. Very well. I shall remember this when you beg me for your life.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DOFED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I see that you've made friends with {1_CivName}. Perhaps they grow too soft and need to spend some time in the gas chamber.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DOFED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>{1_CivName} is not to be trusted. But you can trust me. Oh yes. I would never betray you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>{1_CivName} is a stern ally of mine. There will be consequences to this mindless denouncement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>{1_CivName} is inferior to our two great nations. I am pleased that you have made your sentiments public.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Your declaration of friendship with {1_CivName} brings me to do the same.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Oh great, now the vermin are breeding. Now I have to deal with both you and {1_CivName}? I'll have to teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I share your convictions that {1_CivName} is terribly inferior.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- General Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Join me in war against {1_PlayerName:textkey}, or suffer the consequences that they now face.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_2">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} needs to be taught their superiors. Will you join me in this endeavour?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_COOP_WAR_TIME_1">
			<Text>War must come upon {1_PlayerName:textkey}; they must know the consequences of their tyranny.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>I would like to show the world that Germany has an ally in you. Shall we make a joint Declaration of Friendship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that you have a large number of Units near my borders. There will be consequences if you do not remove them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_PLOT_BUYING_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Your purchase of land in my vicinity has caused some alarm; I hope that it does not reflect your true colours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_PLOT_BUYING_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>The aggressive manner in which you buy up territory is making it clear to me that you are an enemy to the German Empire. Enemies to the German Empire don't last long.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Cease your mindless imperialism, or there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_EXPANSION_WARNING">
			<Text>Your expansion efforts are an insult. Know that there will be consequences for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_1">
			<Text>I hope you're not expecting sycophancy for this?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->	
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_JFD_HITLER_1">
			<Text>I just wanted to let you know that I hate you, and think you deserve nothing more than to be thrown to the wolves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_JFD_HITLER_2">
			<Text>Ah, it's you. I thought it was you; I could smell you all the way over here.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_JFD_HITLER_3">
			<Text>I'm really getting tired of seeing your face. My hope is that one day it'll just melt off, or something.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_JFD_HITLER_4">
			<Text>Ah, it's you. My apologies. Sometimes I get you mixed up with the barbarians I have to swat from time to time. I say barbarians - but you and I both know I mean something else.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>You barely have an army at all! Better not let someone like me know. Oh! Too late, hehe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_MILITARY_2">
			<Text>With an army so weak it's a surprise your empire hasn't succumb to a barbarian invasion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_BULLY_1">
			<Text>It shows just how pathetic you are that you must pick on the innocent; depriving me of the opportunity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_1">
			<Text>I can hear your people wailing in sorrow all the way over in my empire. If you don't do something soon they might just pack up and find a real civilization to live in.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_2">
			<Text>With people so unhappy it's a shock to me that they'd keep you around as their leader.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_CITIES_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that your empire appears to be quite puny. Did you forget to expand your borders or are you just having a little trouble with that?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_POPULATION_1">
			<Text>Travelers have told us that your empire's economy is in pretty sad shape. If you beg a little I might give you a hand. Okay, actually I won't.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>What a sad sight... your empire is so uncultured. What do your citizens do all day, beat rocks together?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_INSULT_CULTURE_2">
			<Text>Rumor has it that your culture is so laughable that even the barbarians are shying away from your lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human is asking the AI for something -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Ridiculous! I will double my efforts because of this!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Bah. Fine. Now get out of my sight.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>You will accept this deal, or there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>You will allow passage between our two nations, or there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>You will pay this tribute to me, or there will be consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Attacked by Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Your people are mostly German anyway; it is time to unite them in the fires of my war machine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>What?! You dare to attack me? Very well; let the fun begin then. Let hell rain fire from the bowels of this war machine!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>Your people are mostly German anyway; it is time to unite them in the fires of my war machine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>Your people are mostly German anyway; it is time to unite them in the fires of my war machine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declaring War on Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>This world cannot be unshackled until you are destroyed. Prepare for war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>Your empire comprises of living space for my people. This day was bound to come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_LAND_2">
			<Text>You are too close for comfort. My empire requires more living space.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>This world must be cleansed in the fires of the German war machine and it shall begin with the conquest of your empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>You should never have let your guard down! Now I take this opportunity to enact the consequences of your weakness!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>This war is my design; I shall die before I surrender.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_DESPERATE_2">
			<Text>This war is my design; I shall die before I surrender.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>I have betrayed you, so that I might honour the German people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>You want peace now? When you are losing so badly? Hah!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_BAD_1">
			<Text>Prepare for the consequences of your damned foolishness!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_BAD_2">
			<Text>You're a real fool, you know?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_BAD_3">
			<Text>Curse you. This will mean grave consequences upon you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_HITLER_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I knew you had better sense than to trifle with Germany.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Das Vaterland
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_GERMANY">
			<Text>Great Generals may be expended to generate a large amount of [ICON_RESEARCH] Science. Non-ranged military land units contribute twice as many points toward the generation of Great Generals through combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_GERMANY_SHORT">
			<Text>Das Vaterland</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Wehrmacht
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_WEHRMACHT_DESC">
			<Text>Wehrmacht</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_WEHRMACHT_TEXT">
			<Text>The Wehrmacht was the name of the armed forces of Germany between 1935 and 1945, meaning Defence Force. Although in English the Wehrmacht is often synonymous with the Heer, the army division of the Wehrmacht, the Wehrmacht actually consists of three individual forces: the Heer (army), the Kriegsmarine (navy) and Luftwaffe (air force).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The German term Wehrmacht technically describes any nation's Armed Forces, thus, Britische Wehrmacht denotes "British Armed Forces." The term Wehrmacht is in Article 47 of the 1919 Weimar Constitution, establishing that: The Reich's President holds supreme command of all armed forces [i.e. the Wehrmacht] of the Reich ("Der Reichspräsident hat den Oberbefehl über die gesamte Wehrmacht des Reiches"). From 1919, Germany's national defence force was known as the Reichswehr, which name was dropped in favor of Wehrmacht on 16 March 1935. In modern day Germany the name Wehrmacht is considered a proper noun for the 1935-45 armed forces, being replaced by Streitkräfte in its original meaning; however, this was not so even some decades after 1945. In English writing Wehrmacht is often used to refer specifically to the land forces (army); the correct German for this is Heer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_WEHRMACHT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Wehrmacht is a unique unit for Nazi Germany, replacing the Infantry. Cheaper than the Infantry, the Wehrmacht starts with the Blitz promotion, allowing it to make one additional attack per turn.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_WEHRMACHT_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Modern Era gunpowder unit that may make one additional attack per turn. Only Nazi Germany may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						SS
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SS_DESC">
			 <Text>SS Commander</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SS_TEXT">
			<Text>The Schutzstaffel was a major paramilitary organization under Adolf Hitler and the Nazi Party (NSDAP) in Nazi Germany, and later throughout German-occupied Europe during World War II. It began with a small guard unit known as the Saal-Schutz ("Hall Security") made up of NSDAP volunteers to provide security for party meetings in Munich. In 1925 Heinrich Himmler joined the unit, which had by then been reformed and given its final name. Under his direction (1929 – 1945) it grew from a small paramilitary formation to one of the most powerful organizations in Nazi Germany. From 1929 until the regime's collapse in 1945, the SS was the foremost agency of security, surveillance, and terror within Germany and German-occupied Europe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SS_HELP">
			 <Text>Uniqe Nazi Great General that may be expended to generate large amount of [ICON_RESEARCH] Science.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SS_STRATEGY">
			 <Text>The SS Commander is a unique unit for Nazi Germany, replacing the Great General. The SS Commander may be expended to generate large amount of [ICON_RESEARCH] Science, as if it were a Great Scientist.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_ULRICH_GREIFELT">
			<Text>Ulrich Greifelt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_ERNST_ROBERT_GRAWITZ">
			<Text>Ernst-Robert Grawitz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_CURT_VON_GOTTBERG">
			<Text>Curt von Gottberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_HERBERT_OTTO_GILLE">
			<Text>Herbert Otto Gille</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_AUGUST_FRANK">
			<Text>August Frank</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_KARL_HERMANN_FRANK">
			<Text>Karl Hermann Frank</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_ALBERT_FORSTER">
			<Text>Albert Forster</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_KARL_FIEHLER">
			<Text>Karl Fiehler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_THEODOR_EICKE">
			<Text>Theodor Eicke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JOACHIM_ALBRECHT_EGGELING">
			<Text>Joachim Albrecht Eggeling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_KARL_VON_EBERSTEIN">
			<Text>Karl von Eberstein</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_OTTO_DIETRICH">
			<Text>Otto Dietrich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_KARL_MARIA_DEMELHBUER">
			<Text>Karl-Maria Demelhuber</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_RICHARD_WALTHER_DARRE">
			<Text>Richard Walther Darre</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_WALTER_BUCH">
			<Text>Walter Buch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_FRANZ_BREITHAUPT">
			<Text>Franz Breithaupt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_PHILIPP_BOUHLER">
			<Text>Philipp Bouhler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_MARTIN_BORMANN">
			<Text>Martin Bormann</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_ERNST_WILHELM_BOHLE">
			<Text>Ernst Wilhelm Bohle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_WILHELM_BITTRICH">
			<Text>Wilhelm Bittrich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_WERNER_BEST">
			<Text>Werner Best</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_GOTTLOB_BERGER">
			<Text>Gottlob Berger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_HERBERT_BACKE">
			<Text>Herbert Backe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_MAX_AMANN">
			<Text>Max Amann</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_FRIEDRICH_ALPERS">
			<Text>Friedrich Alpers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_FRAZ_XAVER_SCHWARZ">
			<Text>Fraz Xaver Schwarz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_PAUL_HAUSSER">
			<Text>Paul Hausser</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_SEPP_DIETRICH">
			<Text>Sepp Dietrich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_KURT_DALUEGE">
			<Text>Kurt Daluege</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_KARL_HANKE">
			<Text>Karl Hanke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_HEINRICH_HIMMLER">
			<Text>Heinrich Himmler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_ERHARD_HEIDEN">
			<Text>Erhard Heiden</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JOSEPH_BERCHTOLD">
			<Text>Joseph Berchtold</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JULIUS_SCHRECK">
			<Text>Julius Schreck</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Blood and Iron
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BISMARCKIAN_GERMANY_SHORT">
			<Text>Blood and Iron</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BISMARCKIAN_GERMANY">
			<Text>Upon conquering a City-State for the first time, receive a free Social Policy. Conquered City-States do not enter [ICON_RESISTANCE] Resistance and provide additional Delegates to the World Congress.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Update>
			<Set Text="[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]{1_NumVotes} from Buildings and World Wonders"/>
			<Where Tag="TXT_KEY_LEAGUE_OVERVIEW_MEMBER_DETAILS_WONDER_VOTES" />
		</Update>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BISMARCK_DELEGATE_HELP">
			<Text>+1 Delegate to the World Congress.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BISMARCK_DELEGATE">
			<Text>JFD: Bismarck Delegate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_FREE_POLICY_GERMANY_SHORT">
			<Text>Free Social Policy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_FREE_POLICY_GERMANY_DESC">
			<Text>Through Blood and Iron we have been afforded a free Social Policy!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Panzer
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_PANZER_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Atomic Era armor unit that may pillage improvements at no additional movement point cost. Only Nazi Germany may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_PANZER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Panzer is a unique unit for Nazi Germany, replacing the Tank. Stronger and faster than the Tank, the Panzer may pillage improvements at no additional [ICON_MOVES] Movement point cost.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Jaeger
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_DESC">
			<Text>Jaeger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_TEXT">
			<Text>Jäger is a German military term adopted in 1631 by the landgrave of Hesse when he first formed an elite infantry unit out of his professional hunters (Jäger) and rangers (Forstleute) in the Hessian Army. During the Age of Enlightenment in German-speaking states (and others influenced by them) Jäger is used to describe elite light infantry, especially skirmishers, scouts, sharpshooters and couriers. Jäger, which means "hunter" or "huntsman" in German, came by extension to denote light infantrymen whose forester background made them suitable for skirmishing as individuals rather than as a drilled and regimented body of soldiers. Often they came from families with a tradition of service to one feudal lord. Initially Jägers made use of their own precision made rifles: a more accurate weapon with a longer range than the muskets used by line troops.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Jaeger is the unique unit for Bismarck's Germany, replacing the Rifleman. The Jaeger earns promotions 50% faster and starts with the first Scouting and Survivalism promotions, allowing it to earn promotions normally only available to recon units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Industrial Era gunpowder unit that earns promotions faster. Starts with the first Scouting and Survivalism promotions and may earn promotions normally only available to recon units. Only Bismarck's Germany may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JAEGER">
			<Text>Feldjäger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JAEGER_HELP">
			<Text>Earns 50% more experience from combat.</Text>
		</Row>
  </Language_en_US>
</GameData>