<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Denmark-Norway
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Dano-Norwegian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_DESC">
			<Text>Dano-Norwegian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Denmark-Norway</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Denmark–Norway is the historiographical name for a former political entity consisting of the united kingdoms of Denmark and Norway, including overseas Norwegian dependencies of Iceland, Greenland, the Faroe Islands, and the Northern Isles. Following the departure of Sweden from the Kalmar Union, and its subsequent dissolution, in 1524 Denmark and Norway entered into another personal union, under Danish hegemony. In 1536 the kingdom of Norway was formally dissolved and integrated into Denmark, and as a consequence its Council of the Realm was abolished. However, Norway continued to have separate institutions and its own laws. Norway was re-established as a kingdom in 1660 after the introduction of absolutism. The personal union of the two kingdoms lasted until 1814, when Norway was ceded to Sweden by the House of Oldenburg after Denmark–Norway's defeat in the Napoleonic wars.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City List-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_01">
			<Text>Copenhagen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_02">
			<Text>Christiania</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_03">
			<Text>Aarhus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_04">
			<Text>Bergen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_05">
			<Text>Aalborg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_06">
			<Text>Trondheim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_07">
			<Text>Odense</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_08">
			<Text>Stavanger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_09">
			<Text>Fredriksberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_10">
			<Text>Kristiansand</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_11">
			<Text>Malmø</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_12">
			<Text>Reykjavik</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_13">
			<Text>Esbjerg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_14">
			<Text>Fredrikstad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_15">
			<Text>Glentofte</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_16">
			<Text>Drammen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_17">
			<Text>Gladsaxe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_18">
			<Text>Skien</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_19">
			<Text>Randers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_20">
			<Text>Tromsø</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_21">
			<Text>Nuuk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_22">
			<Text>Tórshavn</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_23">
			<Text>Kolding</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_24">
			<Text>Tønsberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_25">
			<Text>Horsens</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_26">
			<Text>Ålesund</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_9">
			<Text>Ole</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_8">
			<Text>Ærinbjørn</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_7">
			<Text>Anders</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_6">
			<Text>Roald</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_5">
			<Text>Trygve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_4">
			<Text>Helle</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_3">
			<Text>Eline</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_2">
			<Text>Gertrude</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_1">
			<Text>Sarah Lund</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_0">
			<Text>Ariel</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Christian IV
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN">
			<Text>Christian IV</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_CHRISTIAN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Christian IV, sometimes colloquially referred to as Christian Firtal in Denmark and Christian Kvart or Quart in Norway, was a monarch of the House of Oldenburg who ruled as King of Denmark-Norway from 1588 to 1648. His reign of more than 59 years is the longest of all Danish monarchs. Christian began his personal rule of Denmark in 1596 at the age of 19. He is frequently remembered as one of the most popular, ambitious, and proactive Danish kings, having initiated many reforms and projects. However, his personal obsession with witchcraft led to the public execution of some of his innocent subjects, leading to the greatest number of deaths in Denmark during the Burning Times. He renamed the Norwegian capital Oslo as Christiania after himself, a name used until 1925.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_CHRISTIAN_NAME">
			<Text>Christian IV</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_CHRISTIAN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Denmark-Norway</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_CHRISTIAN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>King of Denmark and Norway, Christian Firtal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_CHRISTIAN_LIVED">
			<Text>1577 - 1648 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_DENMARK_NORWAY_TEXT">
			<Text>Good tidings upon thee, noble King Christian IV, leader of the Kingdoms of Denmark and Norway. Though the time that the three ancient Kingdoms of Scandinavia were one had past, you would inherit a powerful union of Denmark and Norway which dominated the peninsula. Heralded for your great and ambitious character, your 59 year reign would be one of the expansion of the Royal Navy and of Dano-Norwegian interests overseas. Though your clashes with Sweden for dominance over the Baltic Sea would ultimately falter, your endearing efforts to better the lives of your people, and your great love of music and art, would ensure your lasting legacy as a great king of the renaissance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]O beloved Christian, the Kingdoms of Denmark and Norway beckon the return of your rule to re-establish a powerful maritime empire. Can you heed the calling of the ancient crowns of Denmark and Norway? Can you, with good character, be the enlightened king that your people demand? Can you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Diplomacy
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Glorious to meet you! Glorious! I am Christian IV, King of Denmark and Norway. I hope you can stomach your ale, my friend, because while you're with me, there's not a moment that you'll go sober, I'll see to that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Greetings. I am Christian IV, King of Denmark and Norway. I hope that you do not have the unfortunate affliction of witchery. I'd have to burn you if you did.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>What a horrible, uncouth bastard you are.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>You talk too much, and drink too little.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_REPEAT_TRADE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>No, no, no. That simply won't do.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Greetings, you horrible little person.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Greetings, my good friend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>Bahahahah! I heard you were at war. I am simply delighted to see you suffering.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>My good friend, I hope that your war does not go badly for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>What are your troops doing near my borders? I'll have you know, I am a force to be reckoned with, if war it is that you seek.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that you recently purchased some land which I considered to be mine. This rather upsets me. So watch your back from now on.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>Stop buying up all the land. I want some too, you know?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>I could've sworn that I had warned you against your aggressive expansion. Well, now I'll just have to draw up plans to undo the damage you've done to what I consider to be my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>You keep settling all over the place and we're going to have a serious problem.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>You've quite the military, you know that? I'm thoroughly impressed. Do you have a navy to go with that?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>Your economy is famed for its great wealth and virility. Good for you. An ale on you then, I should think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES_1">
			<Text>I welcome you, little City-State.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY_1">
			<Text>Your armies a little on the sad side of things, don't you agree?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>Your military conquests are famed throughout the land. It's such a sad thing to see; an empire stolen from others. It won't last, you know?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_1">
			<Text>No, no, no, no. It's much too soon for that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I never really liked you. Others should know this.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Urgh. You're such an arse, you know that? Now you've gone and sullied both our reputations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_2">
			<Text>Very well. Just know that I have more friends than you and this will most likely lead to your demise. No, it definitely will come back to bite you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DOFED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Ahhh, I've noticed that you've become friends with {1_CivName}. Glad to hear of it. I'm already on good terms with them myself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DOFED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>I recommend that you not get too close with {1_CivName}. If so... we might have problems getting along.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I'll have you know that {1_CivName} and I have worked together in the past, and I have the utmost respect for them. Just so you're aware.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>Glad to hear there are others in the world which share my disgust with {1_CivName}. They are clearly not to be trusted.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Oh, so you're friends with {1_CivName}, too, are you? Very well. I'll declare the same then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Oh great, now the vermin are breeding. Now I have to deal with both you and {1_CivName}? I'll have to teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I share your convictions that {1_CivName} only causes problems for the civilized empires of the world. Perhaps the combination of our denouncements will teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- General Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} is the most wretched human being on this earth. Will you join me in wiping them out?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_COOP_WAR_TIME_1">
			<Text>The time has come for you to join Denmark and Norway in war against {1_PlayerName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>I say: a drink to a blossoming friendship. What say you in return?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I am very displeased with how close your units are to my borders. Remove them at once or there will be serious business between us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_PLOT_BUYING_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Your recent purchase of land near to my borders has given me something to think about when evaluating our friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_PLOT_BUYING_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>If you do not cease your relentless land-grabbing, I will be forced to act against you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>If you do not cease your relentless land-grabbing, I will be forced to act against you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_EXPANSION_WARNING">
			<Text>I am growing very displeased with your rate of expansion, and I advise that you temper it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_1">
			<Text>Ah, excellent! Thank you, my good friend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->	
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_JFD_CHRISTIAN_1">
			<Text>Bahahahahahahah! I hate you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_JFD_CHRISTIAN_2">
			<Text>Ah, it's always nice to see my favorite city-state again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_JFD_CHRISTIAN_3">
			<Text>I'm really getting tired of seeing your face. My hope is that one day you'll just go away or something.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_JFD_CHRISTIAN_4">
			<Text>Ah, it's you. My apologies. Sometimes I get you mixed up with the barbarians I have to swat from time to time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Oh my. Have you just come back from a terrible war, or is your army always that small?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_MILITARY_2">
			<Text>With an army so weak it's a surprise your empire hasn't succumb to a barbarian invasion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_BULLY_1">
			<Text>It shows just how pathetic you are that you must pick on the innocent; depriving me of the opportunity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_1">
			<Text>I can hear your people wailing in sorrow all the way over in my empire. If you don't do something soon they might just pack up and find a real civilization to live in.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_2">
			<Text>Your people are so unhappy. You must be quite the horrible person. Tell them from me that they are more than welcome to join a real civilization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_CITIES_1">
			<Text>Your empire is so tiny I can barely see it on a map! It's really quite pitiful, you know.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_POPULATION_1">
			<Text>Travelers have told us that your empire's economy is in pretty sad shape. If you beg a little I might give you a hand. Okay, actually I won't.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>What a sad sight... your empire is so uncultured.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_INSULT_CULTURE_2">
			<Text>Your empire is the most uncultured thing that I have ever seen. Perhaps I should take over? I would certainly do a better job than you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human is asking the AI for something -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Don't be absurd! I'll do as I will.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Oh alright then. But just this once, and just for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>You have a luxury that I want, and you want to give it to me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>I wish that we didn't have to go through so much hassle just to cross our borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>I'm looking for a bit of assistance; it's a good investment, I assure you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Attacked by Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Absolutely I will fight you! I've been waiting for the chance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Absolutely I will fight you!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>I thought we were getting along so well? Why would you do something like this?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>I thought we were getting along so well? Why would you do something like this?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declaring War on Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>Those lands which you have - yes, those. We'll, sorry to tell you this, but they're actually mine, and I'm going to reclaim them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>Those lands which you have - yes, those. We'll, sorry to tell you this, but they're actually mine, and I'm going to reclaim them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>Those lands which you have - yes, those. We'll, sorry to tell you this, but they're actually mine, and I'm going to reclaim them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>I've been awaiting the day you let your guard down. Don't blame me; it's you're own fault, you know?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>This may be a last-ditch effort, but I shall not see the glory days of my empire fade into the past.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>Yes, yes. I'm backstabbing you; how very miserable. Don't worry, though. I'll put you out of your misery soon.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Oh definitely not. I haven't finished collecting cities from your empire yet.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Good. I knew you'd back down.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_BAD_1">
			<Text>Oh, you little bastard.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_CHRISTIAN_BAD_2">
			<Text>This is going to upset me quite a bit. I need a drink. Then I'll be back to punch you in the face.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Dominium Maris Baltici
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_SHORT">
			<Text>Dominium Maris Baltici</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY">
			<Text>Coastal cities are automatically [ICON_CONNECTED] Connected to the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital and start with three Admiral specialists. Great Admirals may be expended to construct Citadels on water tiles. Receive a free Great Admiral upon discovering Sailing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY">
			<Text>Admiral Specialists</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_DENMARK_NORWAY_HELP">
			<Text>Automatially [ICON_CONNECTED] Connects this city to the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital after discovering the Wheel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_JFD_DENMARK_GENERAL">
			<Text>Admiral</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_JFD_DENMARK_GENERAL_TITLE">
			<Text>Great Admiral Points</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_JFD_DENMARK_GENERAL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Work Admirals to increase a city's [ICON_FOOD] Food output and provide military units built in that city with additional experience. Admirals increase the speed at which Great Admirals are generated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_JFD_DENMARK_GENERAL_SLOTS">
			<Text>Admiral Slots</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Kontreadmiral
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL">
			<Text>Kontreadmiral</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_PEDIA">
			<Text>The Kontreadmiral is the highest active rank in Danish and Norwegian navies and is usually awarded to the head of a command. The rank is equivalent to a Major General in air or ground forces. Kontreadmiral literally means "rear" or "under" admiral, signifying that the rank is below that of the Admiral. The term was coined by the Dutch first as Schoutbynaut, meaning "Supervisor of the night". In 1771, the term was adopted in Denmark-Norway under the reign of Christian VII.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Kontreadmiral is a Dano-Norwegian unique unit, replacing the Great Admiral. The Kontreadmiral may be expended to construct a Citadel improvement on a water tile, incorporating all adajcent tiles into your territory. The Citadel provides a +100% Defense Bonus to friendly military units stationed on it and does 30 damage to enemy units that end the turn adjacent to it. The Citadel may be used by land units to cross water tiles without having to embark, but cannot be built next to another Citadel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Dano-Norwegian Great Admiral that may be expended to construct a Citadel on a water tile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_JFD_SEA_FORTRESS">
			<Text>Citadel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SEA_FORTRESS">
			<Text>Construct a Citadel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_JFD_SEA_FORTRESS_HELP">
			<Text>The Citadel provides a +100% Defense Bonus to friendly military units stationed on it and does 30 damage to enemy units that end the turn adjacent to it. The Citadel may be used by land units to cross water tiles without having to embark.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_JFD_SEA_FORTRESS_REC">
			<Text>The Citadel provides a +100% Defense Bonus to friendly military units stationed on it and does 30 damage to enemy units that end the turn adjacent to it. The Citadel may be used by land units to cross water tiles without having to embark.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Replace Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_IMPROVEMENTS_CITADEL_TEXT">
			<Text>A Citadel is a mighty fortification that can only be constructed by a Great General or the Dano-Norwegian Kontreadmiral, usually near a city or on a particularly defensible piece of terrain, or on a water tile in the case of the Kontreadmiral. The Acropolis in Athens, Greece, is an example of an early powerful Citadel. Such structures were almost impossible to take by direct attack, and they were capable of withstanding protracted sieges before they fell. You can construct a Citadel anywhere within or adjacent to your territory. Upon constructing the Citadel, your borders will expand to assimilate all tiles adjacent to the Citadel. If these new borders claim tiles already owned by another civilization, you will incur a diplomatic penalty as a result. The Citadel provides a +100% Defense Bonus to friendly military units stationed on it and does 30 damage to enemy units that end the turn adjacent to it (damage does not stack with other Citadels). Citadels built on water tiles may be used by land units to cross those tiles without having to embark.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Unique Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_01">
			<Text>Claus Paarss</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_02">
			<Text>Niels Juel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_03">
			<Text>Cort Adeler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_04">
			<Text>Peter Tordenskjold</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_05">
			<Text>Olfert Fischer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_06">
			<Text>Steen Andersen Bille</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_07">
			<Text>Cornelis Tromp</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_08">
			<Text>Peter Christian Petersenr</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_09">
			<Text>Ove Gjedde</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_10">
			<Text>Evert Andersen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_11">
			<Text>Lauritz Galtung</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_12">
			<Text>Corfits Ulfeldt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_13">
			<Text>Kristoffer Throndsen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_14">
			<Text>Christen Thomesen Sehested</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_15">
			<Text>Axel Mowat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_16">
			<Text>Thomas Konow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_17">
			<Text>Niels Juel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_18">
			<Text>Jørgen Jørgensen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_19">
			<Text>Hans Køning</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_20">
			<Text>Lauritz Galtung</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_21">
			<Text>Hans Peter Holm</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_22">
			<Text>Ivar Huitfeldt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_23">
			<Text>Carl Wilhelm Jessen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_24">
			<Text>Henrik Bjelke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_25">
			<Text>Michael Bille</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_26">
			<Text>Christian Thomsen Carl</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_27">
			<Text>Jens Schou Fabricius</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JFD_KONTREADMIRAL_28">
			<Text>Jens Munk</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Mead House
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_MEAD_HALL">
			<Text>Mead Hall</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_MEAD_HALL_HELP">
			<Text>+10% [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great People generation in this City. Starts a "We Love the King Day" in this city when constructed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_MEAD_HALL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Mead Hall is the Dano-Norwegian unique building, replacing the Circus. The Mead Hall increases the speed at which Great People are generated in this city as well as the civilization's [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness. When first constructed in this city, the Mead Hall starts a "We Love the King Day". The Mead Hall does not require this city to have an improved source of [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horses or [ICON_RES_IVORY] Ivory nearby.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_MEAD_HALL_TEXT">
			<Text>In ancient Scandinavia and Germanic Europe a mead hall or feasting hall was initially simply a large building with a single room. From the fifth century to early medieval times such a building was the residence of a lord and his retainers. The mead hall was generally the great hall of the king.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Ski Infantry
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY">
			<Text>Ski Infantry</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Ski Infantry is a Dano-Norwegian unique unit, replacing the Rifleman. Cheaper than the Rifleman, The Ski Infantry receives +2 [ICON_MOVES] Movement and a +50% Attack Bonus if it starts the turn on a Hill tile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Industrial Era gunpowder unit that specializes in fighting in Hills. Only Denmark-Norway may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY_MOVES_INFO">
			<Text>Hill Movement</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY_MOVES_INFO_HELP">
			<Text>Receives +2 [ICON_MOVES] Movement and a +50% Attack Bonus if it starts the turn on a Hill tile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY_MOVES">
			<Text>Hill Movement</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_SKI_INFANTRY_MOVES_HELP">
			<Text>+2 [ICON_MOVES] Movement and a +50% Attack Bonus.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Denmark
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_HARALD_LIVED" />
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_HARALD_LIVED">
			<Text>~920 - 986 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_VIKING_FURY">
			<Text>Embarked units receive +2 [ICON_MOVES] Movement and can disembark at no additional movement point cost. Melee and Gunpowder units start with Amphibious and may pillage improvements at no additional movement point cost.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City List-->
		<Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_COPENHAGEN" />
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_COPENHAGEN">
			<Text>Roskilde</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Beserker
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_DENMARK_BERSERKER_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Medieval Era melee unit that specializes in attacking but does not receive defensive terrain bonuses. Does not require a source of [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron to be built. Only Denmark may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_DENMARK_BERSERKER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Berserker is a Danish unique unit, replacing the Longswordsman. Faster than the Longswordsman, the Berserker is available earlier and receives a +25% Attack Bonus but does not receive defensive terrain bonuses. Unlike the Longswordsman, the Berserker does not require a source of [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron to be built.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Longboat
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LONGBOAT">
			<Text>Longboat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LONGBOAT_TEXT">
			<Text>Longboats (or Longships) were sea vessels made and used by the Vikings from the Nordic countries for trade, commerce, exploration, and warfare during the Viking Age. The longship is characterized as a graceful, long, narrow, light, wooden boat with a shallow-draft hull designed for speed. The ship's shallow draft allowed navigation in waters only one metre deep and permitted beach landings. Longships were fitted with oars along almost the entire length of the boat itself. Later versions sported a rectangular sail on a single mast which was used to replace or augment the effort of the rowers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LONGBOAT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Longboat is a Danish unique unit, replacing the Trireme. Stronger and faster than the Trireme, the Longboat earns promotions 50% faster and can move after attacking. The Longboat provides nearby friendly military land units with a +20% Combat Bonus outside of friendly territory. The Longboat automatically upgrades upon discovering Compass.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LONGBOAT_HELP">
			<Text>Fast Ancient Era naval ranged unit that earns promotions faster and can move after attacking. Provides nearby friendly military land units with a combat bonus outside of friendly territory. Automatically upgrades upon discovering Compass. Only Denmark may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LONGBOAT_UPGRADE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Longboat is a Danish unique unit, replacing the Galleass. Stronger and faster than the Galleass, the Longboat earns promotions 50% faster and can move after attacking. The Longboat provides nearby friendly military land units with a +20% Combat Bonus outside of friendly territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LONGBOAT_UPGRADE_HELP">
			<Text>Fast Medieval Era naval ranged unit that earns promotions faster and can move after attacking. Provides nearby friendly military land units with a combat bonus outside of friendly territory. Only Denmark may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_LAND_UNIT_BONUS">
			<Text>Viking Raider</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_LAND_UNIT_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>+20% Combat Bonus outside of friendly territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_LAND_UNIT_BONUS_LONGBOAT">
			<Text>Viking Longship</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_LAND_UNIT_BONUS_LONGBOAT_HELP">
			<Text>Nearby friendly military land units receive a +20% Combat Bonus outside of friendly territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_EXPERIENCE_BONUS">
			<Text>Experienced Marauder</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_EXPERIENCE_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>Earns 50% more experience from combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Songhai
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_AMPHIB_WARLORD_SHORT">
			<Text>Timbuktu Manuscripts</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_AMPHIB_WARLORD">
			<Text>Receive triple the [ICON_GOLD] Gold from clearing Barbarian encampments and conquering enemy cities. Receive 10% of the [ICON_RESEARCH] Science output of your cities following your [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital's religion in the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_SONGHAI_SCIENCE">
			<Text>JFD: Songhai Science</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_SONGHAI_SCIENCE_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_SONGHAI_TRACKER">
			<Text>Timbuktu Manuscripts</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_SONGHAI_TRACKER_HELP">
			<Text>Provides 10% of the [ICON_RESEARCH] Science output of your cities following your [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital's religion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Songhai
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_MUSLIM_CAVALRY_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Medieval Era mounted unit that is not penalized when attacking cities and is able to receive defensive terrain bonuses. Only Songhai may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_MUSLIM_CAVALRY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Mandekalu Cavalry is the Songhai unique unit, replacing the Knight. Cheaper than the Knight, the Mandekalu Cavalry is not penalized when attacking cities and is able to receive defensive terrain bonuses.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Mud Pyramid Mosque
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_MUD_PYRAMID_MOSQUE_HELP">
			<Text>Increases religious pressure emanating from this city by 50%. Requires no [ICON_GOLD] Gold maintenance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a Shrine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_MUD_PYRAMID_MOSQUE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Mud Pyramid Mosque is the Songhai unique building, replacing the Temple. The Mud Pyramid Mosque increases the [ICON_CULTURE] Culture and [ICON_PEACE] Faith output of this city as well as the religious pressure emenating from this city. The Mud Pyramid Mosque has no maintenance cost. Can only be built if this city contains a Shrine.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>