<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Bavaria
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_BAVARIA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Bavarian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_BAVARIA_DESC">
			<Text>Bavarian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_BAVARIA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Bavaria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Located in the heart of Europe, the Kingdom of Bavaria has a history spanning just over a century, from being one of the largest regions in the German Confederacy to forming an integral part of Germany's cultural and political landscape. Born out of the political turmoil that Napoleon left in central Europe, Bavaria was able to claim itself as an independent nation soon after the Napoleonic Wars. Bavaria's first monarch was Maximilian Joseph I, who was able to steer this nation so that subsequent monarchs would be able to govern effectively over Bavaria's expanse. For most of the 19th century, Bavarian culture was shaped by the rich fairytale-like endeavours that its monarchs, Ludwig II in particular, undertook in the form of castles. With a beautiful winter landscape, Bavaria was, and still is a fantastic location for any form of romanticism. After the First World War, Bavaria ceased to exist as a nation and instead became a region of Germany, but the Bavarian culture remains strong to this day. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Geography</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The landscape of Bavaria is to many one of the most beautiful in the world. Picturesque winter scenes arise when shown with a snowed-over castle in the background, presumably generating a fair amount of the worth of Bavaria's tourist industry. Given that Bavaria shares borders with the mountainous Austria and the Czech Republic, one might expect it to have its fair share of hills; indeed, the Bavarian Alps add to its beauty. Two forest ranges, the Bavarian and the Bohemian, span most of the Czech and Austrian borders and contribute further to this majestical nation. The region also has two major rivers that run through it - the Danube and the Main - the former being one of the best known rivers in Europe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Holy Rome and Early History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Prior to the Holy Roman Empire, the Bavarian state had not yet been conceived in the sense we would look at it today. It had rough borders in the south of Germany, but had no real significance besides being located in the centre of Europe. The Duchy of Bavaria was really the initial mention of Bavaria in any form, but at first, Bavaria never looked like it was getting anywhere. One of the first leaders came to the throne at the age of eight, and while he was able to fight wars against the Slavs to the east later in his reign and build monasteries around Bavaria, he was pressured into resigning as Duke, and subsequently deposed by Charlemagne, the Holy Roman Emperor at the time. While these were some setbacks to Bavaria as a state, it managed to endure in several forms until the end of the Holy Roman Empire regardless, and afterwards forming borders far closer to the current ones.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The Bavarian Electorate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>In 1623, the Electorate of Bavaria was formed out of a power vacuum in the area due to the Thirty Years' War, resulting in rough borders that were getting closer to the current Bavarian lands. The former Duchy of Bavaria was the first initiation of the state to use Munich as its capital, but the Electorate used it for its entire history. This state was part of the loosely-confederated Holy Roman Empire, a "patchwork empire" that had established fragile dominance in the heart of Europe. At the time, Bavaria's crown was essentially independent from Holy Rome in many ways. During the Electorate period, Bavaria only stagnated. The House of Wittelsbach kept Bavaria essentially in the Middle Ages, even into the so-called Enlightenment Era. It was at this time the Illuminati, or "Illuminated Ones", were founded; an underground organization that aimed to promote equality in the state of Bavaria, and later spread in the form of conspiracy theories. Only a few years after the Illuminati were founded, the French Revolution began; Europe, plunged into turmoil, felt it right at the core.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Revolution and Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Right at the start of the uprisings in France, Bavaria was overrun by French troops aiming to liberate it from its monarchy. However, given the weak political situation in Bavaria, people found it hard to find a stable political system. In 1806, Napoleon invaded Germany and founded the Confederation of the Rhine, including Bavaria, now more or less independent, as a client state. A lot of present-day Bavaria's cultural heritage comes from this period, especially the castles dotted around the landscape, notably Neuschwanstein. This iteration of Bavaria spanned around one hundred years, during which it ascended to the German Confederation. The Kingdom of Bavaria saw successive monarchs using their personal wealth to create a legacy in the lands, and during the entire post-revolutionary period, Bavaria prospered as a result of undying patronage and romanticism from the monarchs. The Kingdom fell in 1918, at the end of the First World War. Germany, having lost, deposed all forms of monarchy and founded the new Weimar Republic in the Empire's place. From that point on, Bavaria ceased to exist as an independent nation, instead simply as a part of Germany. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Bavaria Today</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Following the years after the disestablishment of the Kingdom of Bavaria, it became a major political centre of Germany. For example, in 1923, the Nazi Party attempted a coup in Munich to install themselves as Germany's legitimate party, which ultimately failed. To this day, Bavaria as a whole remains the heart of Germany's political system, but also its culture. The tales of the Grimm Brothers, while not explicitly set in Bavaria, are often featured there to take advantage of its breathtaking landscape. Today, tourists come to this corner of Germany if only to see the mountains, forests, rivers and lakes, with castles further assuring the fairytale theme. Bavaria's history makes it far from a fantasy state, though; instead, a vibrant nation, full of culture and exciting history, making it an integral part of the nation of Germany today</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_FACTOID_HEADING">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_BAVARIA_FACTOID_TEXT">
			<Text>The main ruling family of Bavaria, the House of Wittelsbach, dominated Bavarian politics for over seven hundred years, having effective control of whatever Bavarian state existed at the time from around 1214 to 1918.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bavaria is the largest region of Germany, and also one of the oldest. With around 12 million people - roughly a fifth of Germany's total population - Bavaria forms a vital part of the nation.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]King Ludwig II was one of the first to suggest that Kaiser Wilhelm I should take over the whole of Germany; he accepted at a treaty signed in Versailles, which was then occupied by Germany.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City List-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_01">
			<Text>Munich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_02">
			<Text>Regensburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_03">
			<Text>Ingolstadt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_04">
			<Text>Nuremberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_05">
			<Text>Straubing</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_06">
			<Text>Augsburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_07">
			<Text>Landshut</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_08">
			<Text>Freising</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_09">
			<Text>Ansbach</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_10">
			<Text>Bayreuth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_11">
			<Text>Wurzburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_12">
			<Text>Erlangen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_13">
			<Text>Bamberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_14">
			<Text>Friedberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_15">
			<Text>Altotting</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_16">
			<Text>Amberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_17">
			<Text>Kempten</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_18">
			<Text>Muhldorf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_19">
			<Text>Erding</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_20">
			<Text>Speyer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_21">
			<Text>Kaiserslautern</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_22">
			<Text>Landau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_23">
			<Text>Dingolfing</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_24">
			<Text>Frankenthal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_25">
			<Text>Weilheim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_26">
			<Text>Zweibrucken</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_27">
			<Text>Eichstatt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_28">
			<Text>Pfarrkirchen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_29">
			<Text>Kelheim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_30">
			<Text>Mainburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_9">
			<Text>Max Joseph</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_8">
			<Text>Jerome</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_7">
			<Text>Wassily</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_6">
			<Text>Henrik</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_5">
			<Text>Kurt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_4">
			<Text>Florian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_3">
			<Text>Adam the Illuminated</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_2">
			<Text>Elisabeth</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_1">
			<Text>Sophie</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BAVARIA_0">
			<Text>Charlotte</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Ludwig II
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG">
			<Text>Ludwig II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_1">
			<Text>One of the most interesting and eccentric monarchs in history, King Ludwig II, nicknamed the "Fairytale King", was noted for his policies of grandeur within Bavaria. Ludwig came to the throne aged only 18, but subsequently aimed to make his kingdom stand out as a true cultural powerhouse. During his reign, Bavaria fell into political turmoil; it was effectively annexed by Prussia, and later its successor, Germany. However, Ludwig was able to use this to his advantage, and pursued a cultural revival in Bavaria, as he could ignore state affairs to a large extent. With the creation of two palaces in his realm, Ludwig was noted for his intense patronage of the arts; after Richard Wagner's performances moved him, Ludwig commissioned the Neuschwanstein as a homage to Wagner, and as a personal retreat. Ludwig left a legacy as one of Bavaria's greatest monarchs, despite what critics would describe as a madness - he is still revered as a fantastic leader by many Bavarians today.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Ascenscion to the Throne</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Ludwig's father, Maximilian, had him brought up as a child of royalty to ensure that his throne passed to secure hands. Through brutal tutoring and a rigid education program, Ludwig was brought up as a truly royal child, with none of the household telling him he'd be anything other than king. From an early age, he was certainly more than ready to fulfil the role; and ready he had to be. In 1864, Maximilian died after a short illness, thus forcing the youthful Ludwig to take on his post as King of Bavaria. Aged only 18 at the time of his ascension, Ludwig began to pursue policies of grandeur from an early age. Even at an early age, it was obvious that Ludwig had little intention of governing like his father had hoped for him to do. He very rarely attended formal events, instead preferring to govern by going on long trips of the countryside, chatting to farm labourers and spending his time day-dreaming. While this may not sound like the ingredients for a successful monarch, Bavarians appeared to enjoy this minimalist government stance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Prussian Defeat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_3">
			<Text>During Ludwig's early years as monarch, he made many questionable decisions. To start with, when war broke out between the powers of Austria and Prussia, Ludwig backed the former, not realising Prussia's capabilities. The Austro-Bavarian alliance was defeated in the war, leaving Bavaria as little more than a client state of Prussia. However, many officials in Bavaria aimed to maintain sovereignty in their nation, and Ludwig also protested by refusing to bow to the Prussian's will. In 1870, Ludwig was forced to cede Bavaria to the German Confederation, but he kept an unusually large amount of powers to himself. Over the years, Bavaria was able to prosper as part of this larger state, but they retained and revered Ludwig as their leader.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Prussian Defeat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Ludwig's sexuality is something of dispute among scholars; however, one thing that he truly did love was arts and culture. In a letter to his only fiancée, Sophia Charlotte, Ludwig wrote, "The main substance of our relationship has always been ... Richard Wagner's remarkable and deeply moving destiny." This implied that he had little interest in sexual desire, and instead his true love lay in the world of creativity and imagination. However, Ludwig never came out as openly homosexual, though it was not a criminal act in Bavaria. The reasoning was that the Prussians had outlawed it, and being in partial control of their country, Ludwig had no choice but to keep it as secret as possible.[NEWLINE][NWLINE]Over the course of his reign, Ludwig build three large complexes in total, all of which were funded by the crown expenses. They were, in part, inspired by Wagner; Neuschwanstein, one of Ludwig's proudest achievements, was directly made from his works. Such endeavours earnt him his reputation as the Fairytale King, not quite in touch with the real world, but doing the best he could to make his world appear for others. Even today, Ludwig's constructions have usage in Bavaria's tourism industry, Neuschwanstein contributing to it in no small part.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Later Reign</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_5">
			<Text>While Ludwig had been able to use only his funds to finance his projects across the country, this did not make Bavaria immune to falling into economic crisis. In 1885, Ludwig found himself 14 million marks in debt due to his excessive funding of all things cultural. Though Ludwig's ministers advised him heavily to start paying off the debt, Ludwig refused and instead borrowed yet more from other European royal families. The Bavarian Cabinet were dismissed, but they didn't go without a fight. Declaring Ludwig as insane, they hatched a plot to depose him and put Luitpold in his place as king. By piecing together a report on Ludwig, he was declared insane on the 10th of June 1886, and deposed the same day. The King was at Neuschwanstein at the time, having only been completed for a matter of months. Though many peasants tried to support Ludwig, they were pushed aside, and Luitpold became King of Bavaria. Three days later, Ludwig went out for a walk with his personal doctor, Gudden, and was found dead in Lake Starnberg after a few hours, along with Gudden. The exact circumstances of his death remain unknown.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Judgement of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Though notorious for heavily indebting himself, Ludwig is still known to Bavarians as a good monarch, one who managed to put Bavaria on the globe and establish a rich cultural legacy. Ludwig's reign, in its entirety, is one of the strangest and most fascinating in world history. While a good monarch is meant to govern for the good of the people, Ludwig failed to do so in many ways, yet he is still recognized as a good monarch. The reason for this is likely the romanticism that he brought upon Bavaria, and perhaps even the wealth of culture he gave back to it. Ludwig was also noted for talking to people of all classes, meaning he had a broad understanding of what was going on. Furthermore, he took responsibility in indebting himself and not the state in his ambitions; another sign of good leadership. Though he carried out few political acts that would forever shape the world, he truly romanticised Bavaria in a way no other monarch has been able to do to their own land, and likely never will again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TEXT_7">
			<Text>King Ludwig II was one of the first to suggest that Kaiser Wilhelm I should take over the whole of Germany; he accepted at a treaty signed in Versailles, which was then occupied by Germany. This was done to help avoid another war with France.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Though Ludwig waited around 15 years for Neuschwanstein to be in a state he could move into, he spent less than two years in it before he was deposed. By 1892, most work on the castle stopped, and it is still not technically complete to this day.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_NAME">
			<Text>Ludwig II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Bavaria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_TITLES_1">
			<Text>King of Bavaria, Count Palatine of the Rhine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_LUDWIG_LIVED">
			<Text>1845 - 1886 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_BAVARIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Glory and nobility to you, fabled King of Bavaria, Ludwig II. Acceding at the age of 18, you would oversee the loss of Bavarian sovereignty to the German unification, yet your reign would one of lasting significance. A King beloved by his people, and a Kingdom idealised in his dreams, your lasting legacy would be your enduring love of beauty and art. The opulent castles of Neuschwanstein and Linderhoff, and your endearing patronage of the operas of Richard Wagner, still stand as testimony to an age of fantasy and fairy tales now lost, and assert the independence of the Bavarian identity of which you epitomised.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Great and visionary Prince, the Bavarian Kingdom stands barren of the culture and magnificence that once adorned it. Can you raise great monuments and wonders to the glory of these lands? Can you inspire works of great renown and beauty to strengthen the character of the Bavarian nation? Can you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Diplomacy
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Ahem. I am Ludwig II, King of Bavaria. I assure you, you sleep not. You have stumbled upon a dream, yes - no, a fantasty; a paradise unrivalled on all the earth - but it is a fantasy of mine into which you step. My dream in which I hope you'll stay a while.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>You made it. I am Ludwig II, King of Bavaria. Take in, for a moment, the fresh, alpine air, and if you will, listen to the silence around us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I shall now retreat to one of my great sanctums for good.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>By God you're boring.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_REPEAT_TRADE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>Will you just hurry this along?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>I quite like you, you know that?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I heard from my ministers that you were at war. I think it's very quaint that they call what you've gotten yourself into a war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I hope your war ends soon. I would hate to never see your pretty face again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Soldiers marching upon my borders. How dare you? Get rid of them at once!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>Stop what you're doing! That land is better to belong to me and my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>You've started to buy up territory that would look better as mine. I want to warn you against that. Do not come between me and my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>You keep settling over the land, leaving nothing for me and my people. Do not awaken me from this dream of mine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>You've started to settle upon lands that would look better as mine. I want to warn you against that. Do not come between me and my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Welcome back. Since you were last here, I've heard you've gotten yourself quite a powerful military.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>I've heard of your great wealth, and I've been looking for someone to join me in my next project, you know?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES_1">
			<Text>My dear, if the size of your empire is anything to go by...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY_1">
			<Text>I feel much safer knowing how small your army is.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>I know what you are, barbarian. I won't have you destroy this beautiful land.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_1">
			<Text>No, sorry. I couldn't stand the thought of it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You've caused too much trouble for me to stand idly by. You are a threat to the stability of the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>What is wrong with you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- General Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>What do you say to a 'special' relationship, hm?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Why don't you get your armies out of my base?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PLOT_BUYING_WARNING_1">
			<Text>You keep purchasing land like this and we're going to have a problem.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_PLOT_BUYING_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I warned you that we would have a problem, and now we have one. Stop your land deals at once!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Your aggressive expansion is getting on my nerves. Won't you just stop?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_EXPANSION_WARNING">
			<Text>You aggressive expansion is going to be an issue for me in the future, if you don't stop.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_1">
			<Text>That was good of you to return one of my subjects.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->	
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>Don't feel bad about your culture. You couldn't possibly compete with Bavaria.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_INSULT_CULTURE_2">
			<Text>Your culture is so underwhelming. Try promoting some art now and again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human is asking the AI for something -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Um, no?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Fine, fine. It wasn't going to make for good land anyway.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>You have a resource that would look good in one of my castles</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>What are you waiting for? Come, Bavaria awaits your gaze. Let beauty be not constrained by political borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>I could use your help.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Attacked by Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You seek only to destroy my beauty, but it is only immortalised thus.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>I would not be sad to see my office taken, if only I could guarantee the security of my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>This is awkward. I liked you, and I am broken by this action.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>I would not be sad to see my office taken, if only I could guarantee the security of my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declaring War on Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>Glorious ballads will be sung about the legendary battles to come. Let us go to war, then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>So many castle-less hills upon your landscape, it is too much to bare!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>When I sleep, I dream, and whence all the world is mine, I may dream forever.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>I've been waiting for this day to come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>One last effort, alright? Once last dance upon the fields of battle, before all the world is vomited from my dreams.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>Regretfully, I must inform you of this betrayal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>No way. We've just gotten started.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Good.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_LUDWIG_BAD_2">
			<Text>That's upsetting.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						The Swan King
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BAVARIA_SHORT">
			<Text>The Swan King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BAVARIA">
			<Text>Each World Wonder provides +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture. Each city containing a World Wonder receives a slot for a Great Work of Music which, when filled, provides +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when constructing Wonders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BAVARIAN_PRODUCTION">
			<Text>JFD: Bavarian Wonder Production</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BAVARIAN_PRODUCTION_HELP">
			<Text>+25% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when constructing Wonders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BAVARIAN_MUSIC">
			<Text>Great Work of Music Slot</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BAVARIAN_MUSIC_HELP">
			<Text>Contains a slot for a Great Work of Music which, when filled provides +25% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when constructing Wonders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BAVARIAN_TOURISM">
			<Text>JFD: Bavarian Tourism</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_BAVARIAN_TOURISM_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Hartschier
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_HARTSCHIER">
			<Text>Hartschier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_HARTSCHIER_TEXT">
			<Text>An elite palace guard troop, the Hartschiere served in the court of Bavaria since the Middle Ages until the end of the first World War. Their name was most probably derived from the Italian word for archer: arciere. Only soldiers of Immaculate conduct and prestige could be promoted to this exclusive band of soldiers, whose commander was appointed by the Monarch of Bavaria himself. The Hartschiere were lavishly outfitted with white supra vests and helmets fashioned from tin and brass with a lion on top. Armed with rapier-like swords and halberds, the role of the late Bavarian Hartschiere was mostly ceremonial and served no use on the war front. After the demise of the Empire of Germany, the Hartschiere were abolished in 1918.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_HARTSCHIER_HELP">
			<Text>Powerful Renaissance Era melee unit that specializes in fighting in rough terrain and defeating mounted units. When stationed on a Schloss, the Hartschier receives a defense bonus and provides +3 [ICON_GOLD] Gold. Does not require a source of [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horses to be built. Cannot upgrade, but does not obsolete. Only Bavaria may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_HARTSCHIER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Hartschier is the Bavarian unique unit, replacing the Lancer. Slower than the Lancer, the Hartschier receives a +25% Defense Bonus in rough terrain as well as a +33% Combat Bonus against mounted units. Additionally, the Hartschier receives a +50% Defense Bonus and provides +3 [ICON_GOLD] Gold when stationed on a Schloss. Unlike the Lancer, the Hartschier is a melee unit, and as such does not receive the same penalties as the Lancer. Unlike the Lancer, the Hartschier does not require a source of [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horses to be built. The Hartschier cannot upgrade, but it also does not obsolete.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_HUBERTUSODEN">
			<Text>Order of Saint Hubertus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_HUBERTUSODEN_HELP">
			<Text>+25% Defense Bonus in rough terrain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_HARTSCHIER">
			<Text>Bavarian Ceremonial Guard</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_HARTSCHIER_HELP">
			<Text>When stationed on a Schloss, this unit recives a +50% Defense Bonus and provides +3 [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Schloss
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_JFD_SCHLOSS_REC">
			<Text>The Schloss provides [ICON_CULTURE] Culture as well as additional [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for each adjacent Mountain. Upon completion, the Schloss generates a burst of [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Musician points in the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital equal to three times your [ICON_CULTURE] Culture output.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_SCHLOSS">
			<Text>Construct a Schloss</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_JFD_SCHLOSS_HELP">
			<Text>The Schloss provides [ICON_CULTURE] Culture as well as additional [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for each adjacent Mountain. Upon completion, the Schloss generates a burst of [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Musician points in the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital equal to three times your [ICON_CULTURE] Culture output.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_IMPROVEMENTS_JFD_SCHLOSS_HELP">
			<Text>The Schloss provides +3 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture as well as an additional +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for each adjacent Mountain. It can only be built on a Hill tile and cannot be built adjacent to another Schloss. Upon completion, the Schloss generates a burst of [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Musician points in the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital equal to three times your [ICON_CULTURE] Culture output. Once completed, the Schloss cannot be removed. Only Bavaria may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_JFD_SCHLOSS">
			<Text>Schloss</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_IMPROVEMENTS_JFD_SCHLOSS_TEXT">
			<Text>Closely related to the French word "Chateau" in meaning, a Schloss is a type of castle that is often used as a sort of second home for nobility. Schlosser were not known for having many defensive components built into them, only really built for purposes of showing off wealth and complementing the nobility's extravagant lifestyle. In Bavaria in particular, Schlosser were designed to have a classical revival theme around them, with true Enlightenment era architecture. Often, a Schloss would have several other features to give even more of an impression of being incredibly wealthy; a "Wasserschloss", which loosely translates to "Water Castle", was simply a Schloss with a moat. This would have been unnecessary for purposes of defense - very few people thought that as an integral part of their castles at the time - but it showed of wealth and grandeur greatly, adding to the romanticism of the design. The interior of these buildings would have also been very nicely decorated, adding to the general feel of the castle as a getaway for the rich. Neuschwanstein Castle - one of the most expensive and luxurious castles build in world history - is known as "Schloss Neuschwanstein" in Germany, making it possibly the strongest contender for the finest example of a Schloss.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Schloss provides +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture as well as an additional +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for each adjacent Mountain. It can only be built on a Hill tile and cannot be built adjacent to another Schloss. Upon completion, the Schloss generates a burst of [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Musician points in the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital equal to three times your [ICON_CULTURE] Culture output. Once completed, the Schloss cannot be removed. Only Bavaria may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>