<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 1/4/2014 8:45:16 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--POLAND (PILSUDSKI)-->
		<!-- City Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_01">
			<Text>Poznan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_02">
			<Text>Lwow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_03">
			<Text>Wilno</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_04">
			<Text>Lodz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_05">
			<Text>Lublin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_06">
			<Text>Gdynia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_07">
			<Text>Nowogrodek</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_08">
			<Text>Stanislawow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_09">
			<Text>Brzesc nad Bugiem</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_10">
			<Text>Tarnopol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_11">
			<Text>Kielce</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_12">
			<Text>Luck</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_13">
			<Text>Czestochowa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_14">
			<Text>Katowice</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_15">
			<Text>Bialystok</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_16">
			<Text>Rzeszow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_17">
			<Text>Tarnow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_18">
			<Text>Plock</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_19">
			<Text>Chorzow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_20">
			<Text>Sosnowiec</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_21">
			<Text>Konin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_22">
			<Text>Bydgoszcz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_23">
			<Text>Radom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_24">
			<Text>Przemysl</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_25">
			<Text>Kalisz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_26">
			<Text>Sandomierz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_27">
			<Text>Ostroleka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_28">
			<Text>Zakopane</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_29">
			<Text>Pila</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_30">
			<Text>Moscice</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_31">
			<Text>Nowy Sacz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_32">
			<Text>Krosno</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_33">
			<Text>Jaslo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_34">
			<Text>Sanok</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_35">
			<Text>Wizna</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_01">
			<Text>Kwinto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_02">
			<Text>Natasza</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_03">
			<Text>Dyzma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_04">
			<Text>Bór</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_05">
			<Text>Kramer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_06">
			<Text>Pilecki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_07">
			<Text>Sosnowski</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_08">
			<Text>Pola Negri</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_09">
			<Text>Faustyna</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_10">
			<Text>Hennelowa</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_11">
			<Text>Wieniawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--PILSUDSKI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_PILSUDSKI">
			<Text>Pilsudski</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_PILSUDSKI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_PILSUDSKI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Józef Klemens Piłsudski was a Polish statesman; Chief of State (1918 – 1922), "First Marshal of Poland" (from 1920), and de facto leader (1926 – 1935) of the Second Polish Republic, Minister of Military Affairs. From mid-World War I he had a major influence in Poland's politics, and was an important figure on the European political scene. He was the person most responsible for the creation of the Second Republic of Poland in 1918, 123 years after it had been taken over by Russia, Austria and Prussia. Under Piłsudski, Poland annexed Vilnius from Lithuania following Żeligowski's Mutiny but was unable to incorporate most of his Lithuanian homeland into the newly resurrected Polish State. He believed in a multicultural Poland with recognition of numerous ethnic and religious nationalities. His arch-rival Roman Dmowski by contrast called for a purified Poland based on Polish-speaking Catholics with little role for minorities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_PILSUDSKI_LIVED">
			<Text>1867 - 1935 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_PILSUDSKI_NAME">
			<Text>Pilsudski</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_PILSUDSKI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Poland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_PILSUDSKI_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Chief of State[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]First Marshal of Poland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_PILSUDSKI_DAWN">
			<Text>Hail Marshal Pilsudski, Minister of Military Affairs and Chief of State of the Second Polish Republic! Your valiant actions and political foresight would secure your position as the saviour of the Polish nation, and that of a hero to be remembered by generations. At the turn of the 20th century, Poland had been under foreign rule for more than one hundred years. Thanks to your involvement in the creation of the Polish Legions during World War I, the cause of Polish independence would re-surface and captivate the hearts and minds of many. Despite your imprisonment at the hands of the Germans, and the dissolution of the Legions, Poland would declare independence on November 11th, 1918. Over the course of six wars, after having been nearly defeated by the land-hungry Soviet armies, the re-emerging country would firmly establish its borders and proceed to build a strong, industrially and culturally sound nation in the heart of Europe. However, not a state strong enough to withstand the onslaught that would come mere two decades later.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Marshal Pilsudski, the people of Poland call out your name and wish for you to return and lead them once again to glory and triumph. Will you answer the call, and assume supreme command once more? Will you once again put your life at stake for the independence of your country? Will you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MIRACLE OF THE VISTULA-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI">
			<Text>Military units receive a +25% Combat Bonus and earn promotions 50% faster while at war with a stronger foe. Workers improve tiles 25% faster and can build lesser Manufactories and Estates after discovering Industrialization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_POLAND_PILSUDSKI_SHORT">
			<Text>Miracle of the Vistula</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_PILSUDSKI">
			<Text>Miracle of the Vistula</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_PILSUDSKI_HELP">
			<Text>+25% Combat Bonus. Earns 50% more experience from combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLICY_JFD_POLAND_WORKERS">
			<Text>Workers construct tile improvements 25% faster.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_JFD_POLISH_MANUFACTORY">
			<Text>Polish Manufactory</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_JFD_POLISH_CUSTOMS_HOUSE">
			<Text>Polish Estate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_IMPROVEMENTS_JFD_POLISH_CUSTOMS_HOUSE_TEXT">
			<Text>An Estate is a type of rural residence, often big, expensive and lavishly decorated. As a seat of the local noble, an estate was a measure of his, or hers, personal wealth and social standing. An estate would often also encompass large swathes of arable land, meadows and pastures. Produce and livestock from those lands was the primary source of income for the estate. The richest magnates often employed private armies to secure their possessions against outside raids - or even against royal forces, if a noble was at odds with the king.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_IMPROVEMENTS_JFD_POLISH_MANUFACTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>A Manufactory is a plant consisting of one or more buildings in which things are built. The buildings might be foundries, factories, assembly lines, and so forth, usually all working on related items - the foundry creates the steel that the factory rolls into sheets which the workers on the assembly line make into cans, and so forth. A well-run Manufactory can be incredibly productive.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--UHLAN-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_UHLAN_ARMOUR">
			<Text>Attack Bonus vs Armor (25)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_UHLAN_ARMOUR_HELP">
			<Text>+25% Attack Bonus against armor units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_UHLAN_COMBUSTION">
			<Text>Combustion Upgrade</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_UHLAN_COMBUSTION_HELP">
			<Text>Receives +22 [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength after discovering Combustion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_UHLAN">
			<Text>Legiony Polskie</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_UHLAN_HELP">
			<Text>This unit damages adjacent enemy land units and may make one additional attack whenever it defeats an enemy unit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LEG_UHLAN">
			<Text>Legionary Uhlan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_JFD_LEG_UHLAN">
			<Text>Fast Industrial Era mounted unit that receives additional [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength after discovering Combustion and specializes in defeating armor units. Damages adjacent enemy land units and may make one additional attack whenever it defeats an enemy military unit. Only Pilsudski's Poland may built it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_LEG_UHLAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Legionary Uhlan is a unique unit for Pilsudski's Poland, replacing the Cavalry. Faster than the Cavalry, the Legionary Uhlan receives a +25% Attack Bonus against armor units as well as an additional +22 [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength after discovering Combustion. Additionally, the Legionary Uhlan damages adjacent enemy land units and may make one additional attack whenever it defeats an enemy military unit. Unlike the Cavalry, the Legionary Uhlan upgrades into the Tank.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_LEG_UHLAN_TEXT">
			<Text>The Polish Legions were created in 1914, as an independent unit within the Austro-Hungarian Army. With personnel hailing from Austrian-held part of Poland called Galicia, they moved out to meet the Russians in battle on Polish soil. In 1916 the Legions were officially renamed to Polish Auxiliary Force, but the old name remained customary, and with it, the kind of elan of the unit was carried over. Even though the force was dissolved in the course of the war, officers and soldiers of the Legion moved on to create the backbone of the Polish Army after regaining independence in 1918. Many of the veterans of the Legions became important military and political figures of the interwar period in Poland, and were highly respected. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--PZL.23-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_PZL23">
			<Text>Combat Bonus vs Land (50)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_PZL23_HELP">
			<Text>+50% Combat Bonus against land units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_PZL23">
			<Text>PZL.23</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_JFD_PZL23">
			<Text>Powerful Atomic Era fighter air unit that operates in a larger area and specializes in defeating land, hover and bomber air units. Only Pilsudski's Poland may built it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_PZL23_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The PZL.23 is a unique unit for Pilsudski's Poland, replacing the Fighter. Stronger than the Fighter, the PZL.23 has a larger operational range and receives a +50% Combat Bonus against land units as well as a +150% Combat Bonus against hover and bomber air units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JFD_PZL23_TEXT">
			<Text>The PZL.23 Karas ("Crucian"), was a Polish light bomber, designed in 1934 and introduced into the Polish Air Force in 1936. It was a full-metal monoplane. It took three crewmembers, could carry up to 700kg of bombs, and sported two machine guns for self-defence. Despite initial engine problems, the design became popular and was met with interest in the Romanian and Bulgarian Air Forces. Although outnumbered in the German invasion of Poland in 1939 and obsolete in comparison to superior German designs, the PZL.23 aircraft carried out succesful attacks on German armoured columns. After the war, it became a symbol of pre-war Polish Air Force, and miniature modellers' favourite. </Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>